Shubham Nagota

Full Stack Engineer

\(+91-9827656400

in linkedin.com/in/shubhamnagota

github.com/shubhamnagota

Summary

More than 3 years of professional experience in planning, implementing and maintaining full-stack web applications. I have experience working in diverse environments both as part of a team and as an individual. I am a **quick learner**, and I have a **will do attitude** with **time management** skills.

Work History

Full Stack Developer - Team Lead

01/2020 - Present

Byju's

POMS

- 1. Designed and implemented a full-stack web app that helped manage premium account experience for Byju's customers.
- 2. Collaborated with quality assurance, end-users, and other teams in our organization to deliver quality products based on the requirements.
- 3. Worked with external teams to develop OKRs for our product and delivered on those guidelines.
- 4. Followed best coding practices to make sure quality code is delivered.

Software Engineer

06/2019 - 12/2019

Impact Analytics

Belk APS

- 1. Working on End to End Development of a website as a single full stack developer in the team.
- 2. Working on building a website from scratch in ReactJS, NodeJS and Postgres with Support of ES6.
- 3. Implemented Generic Modules to be used by backend application.

Software Engineer

10/2018 - 06/2019

GE Digital

• Rideam

- 1. Working on End to End Development of a website as a single full stack developer in the team.
- 2. Working on building a website from scratch in ReactJS, NodeJS and Postgres with Support of ES6.
- 3. Implemented Generic Modules to be used by backend application.

• FireLine

- 1. Worked on End to End Development of a web application as a single full stack developer in the team.
- 2.Implementing new Features like handling unique data, removing dependencies and maintaining data consistency in the project which makes the product more reliable.
- 3.Creating and maintaining wide Range of component architecture to make a website more responsive.

Software Engineer

10/2017 - 09/2018

Motorola Solutions

- 1) Mainly work on a server-side team which involves handling of python code and writing lots of scripts.
- 2) Writing scripts for handling a large amount of CSV data to process and get the useful extracted data.
- 3) Writing scripts to use the extracted data and generate dynamic SQLs for the database.

Skills

NodeJS

A good understanding of NodeJS that helps to use JavaScript to develop

real-time, fast, scalable, data-driven web applications.

Python

Writing server-side application and data operational logic.

ReactJS and HTML/CSS

Worked with latest react versions and hooks with production ready code.

Data Structures

Familiarity with all Data Structure Concepts with their Implementation.

NoSQL Databases

Have worked on document store databases like MongoDB, Firebase

Realtime Database.

RDBMS

Have in depth understanding of relational databases like Sqlite, MySQL,

OracleSQL and PostgreSQL.

AWS and Docker

Worked on services like EC2, S3, Elastic Beanstalk with Docker.

Projects

Project Title: Role Based Access Control

Stack : Core NodeJS

GitHub Link : https://github.com/shubhamnagota/RoleBasedAccessControl

Description: This is a project which let's you check the actions, user can perform on the resources. It

manages everything in memory. There is no framework or database used.

Project Title: WeLeakInfo Scrapper

Stack: Python, Selenium (Browser Automation), CSV

GitHub Link : https://github.com/shubhamnagota/WeLeakInfoScrapper

Description: WeLeakInfo Scrapper is a project that can be used to check https://search.weleakinfo.com for any personal data compromised. You just have to change the input file given with the project itself according to

your needs and it will generate a csv for output data.

Project Title : Sudoku Puzzle Checker

Stack : NodeJS, JSON, ES6

GitHub Link : https://github.com/shubhamnagota/SudokuPuzzleChecker

Description : Sudoku Puzzle Checker is an application which is used to validate the sudoku board can be

solved or not. The project includes a input.json file, which is used to provide sample boards to check for validations.

Project Title : Tell2Me

Stack: NodeJS, MongoDB, ExpressJS, Angular4, ES6, Heroku

Application Link: http://tell2me.herokuapp.com

Description: Tell2Me is a web application, which allow users to send messages anonymously to users who are registered mentioning their username. It is general website to get the feedback or comments about you.

Project Title: Node Web Application Server

Stack : NodeJS

Application Link: https://github.com/shubhamnagota/NodeWebApplicationServer

Description: A server implemented using NodeJS which is replica of J2EE Web server. It handle request, response, session tracking, cookies, application object, forwarding, server side scripting etc. as J2EE Compliant web server. It enables the programmer to maintain server side code using Java Script.

Project Title : Recallify

Stack : NodeJS, ExpressJS, ReactJS, ReduxJS, MongoDB, ES6, Firebase, Google Authentication

Application Link: http://recallify-words.firebaseapp.com

Description: Recallify is a simple web application, which lets you remember the words.

Education

Bachelor of Engineering

2013 - 2017

Mahakal Institute Of Technology

Bachelor Of Engineering in Computer Science 2017 - CGPA 7.65

Certificates

- Oracle Database 11g from Oracle University (Classroom Course)
- MongoDB with NodeJS online course from MongoDB University (Online Course)
- Coursera Course, Programming for Everybody Python (Online Course)
- Coursera Course, Front-End JavaScript Frameworks: Angular (Online Course)

Created with **TVisualCV**